# XENNETHIA JANE R. BIEN

Ph5 Blk 18 Lot 21 Eastwood Residences, Brgy. San Isidro,

Rodriguez, Rizal, Philippines

Mobile No.: (+63) 976-127-9541 Email: bienxennethia@gmail.com

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVES**

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 3 years of related experience. Ready to help the team achieve company goals.

#### **SKILLS:**

- Able to adapt to new surroundings, team player
- Leadership and Communication Skills
- Front End Languages: JSP, HTML5, CSS/SCSS, & Javascript
- Frameworks: Angular, jQuery, Wordpress, Laravel, & AEM
- Back End Languages: Java, Javascript, & PHP
- Tools: Visual Studio, IntelliJ & iTerm
- Accessibility Testing Tools: Voiceover & aXe Devtools
- Task & Project Management: JIRA, Bitbucket, Git & Sourcetree
- Methodologies: Agile
- Other: Frontend Testing, Responsive design, CSS media queries & Accessibility function

## **WORK EXPERIENCES:**

July – October 2019

## **Telcom Live Content Inc.**

Software Engineer (Intern)

- Collaborated effectively with members of the software development team and personnel in other departments.
- Partnered with team members to learn best practices in software design.
- Worked with developers to identify and remove software bugs and recreated the company's website into CMS using Django Framework.
- Studied how the Sahana Eden works, an Open Source Humanitarian Platform, which uses Web2py Framework.
- Created a Disaster Management System which is the same as Sahana Eden but it was built using Django Framework.

January 2020 - February 2022

# Go BeyondStudios Inc. (Code and Theory - Manila)

Jr. Back-end Developer

- Identified issues, analyzed information and provided solutions to problems.
- Learned new skills and applied to daily tasks to improve efficiency and productivity.

- Attended AEM and WordPress training to work on different projects.
- Worked on AEM 6.5.
- Working on one or more specific modules within a large software system scope.
- Worked on AEM Sling models, Sightly and Touch UI development and developed code using JSP, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, and CSS in CRXDE to build code blocks for components.
- Used JIRA for bug tracking and project tracking.
- Experience working in an agile environment, involved in daily standup meetings,

March 2022 - Present

# Go BeyondStudios Inc. (Code and Theory - Manila)

Fullstack AEM Developer

- Experience in developing components using Sightly Templating System.
- Investigates issues by reviewing/debugging code, provides fixes (analyze and fix bugs) and workarounds.
- Collaborate and add value through participation in peer code reviews, provide comments and suggestions, work with cross functional teams to achieve goals.
- On-board new developers assigned on AEM project.
- Experienced developing websites with Accessibility features and testing using VoiceOver and aXe Devtools.

#### **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

## **BS** in Information Technology

November 2016 - December 2019

# **University of the East - Manila Campus**

Sampaloc, Manila

- CHED Scholarship
- 4th Year Exemplary Academic Performance
- 4th Year Passer of Programming Skills Evaluation
- **Microsoft Technology Associate:** Introduction to Programming using HTML and CSS Certified 2019
- **Microsoft Technology Associate:** Introduction to Programming using Python Certified 2019

# **BS** in Information Technology

May 2015 - September 2016

# **AMA Computer University - East Rizal Campus**

Antipolo City, Rizal

## Secondary:

2011 - 2015

## Gov. Isidro S. Rodriguez Sr. MNHS

Cainta, Rizal

- President of Supreme Student Government, SY 2014-2015
- School Leadership Awardee, SY 2014-2015
- Vice-President Leadership Awardee, 2015



# xennethia.jane.bien@codeandtheory.com

Sick Leave

Vacation Leave

sickday.manila@codeandtheory.com
ph.hr@codeandtheory.com
SL Ticket
VL Ticket